ALARM
I always pray before going to bed.
I pray I get too sick
to get up in the morning…
so that I can't go to school.
I pray I have an accident
and wake up two years later,
already graduated.
I'm not afraid of dying.
-Hello.
That's because…
school is hell, which is worse.
-Isn't that Dae-seok?
-Hey, Dae-seok!
-Dae-seok!
-Hey, step back from there!
-Who's that?
-It's Dae-seok, right?
-Get down. Stop!
-What are you doing?
Park Dae-seok! That's dangerous!
-Dae-seok!
-Watch out!
-It's dangerous!
-Get down!
Hey, shouldn't we call the police?
Call them.
Hey! Get down!
From today, the Daehan High outcast is…
Drumroll, please!
Park Dae-seok!
-Applause!
We will now proceed
with the outcast stick transfer ceremony.
Kim Gyeong-min, the former outcast.
Step forward!
-Get up and take it.
-Get up, you rude bastard.
Hand over the outcast stick!
What do you think you're doing in class?
A decreasing exponential function…
Put your phone away already.
Man, this online lecture
is way more helpful.
You should teach better.
X plus one and…
Watch what you say.
You're just a temp, not a real teacher.
Want a permanent job? I can talk to Dad.
Wow, what a sweet deal.
So just
cut the crap and carry on.
I've had it with you, bastard.
You'd be a helpless jerk without your dad.
Dae-seok!
Is this a mutiny? I like this.
-All right!
-Gwang-su, stop it!
-Why suddenly act up?
-Guys, help!
-Why? You fucking bastard!
-Eyes ahead.
Guys, help him!
-Why now?
-You hear me?
-Why is he being so cocky?
-Why are you all just watching?
OUTCAST STICK
I hope you'll be responsible
and do well in your new role.
And that wraps up
the outcast stick transfer ceremony!
Let's give it up for him!
Dae-seok.
Smile.
You fucking bastard.
Let's go say hi.
Our dear Gyeong-min should join us.
Come on.
Fuck yeah!
Guys, starting today, this fucking bitch
is the new outcast at Daehan High.
Say hello.
Hello.
I'm Park Dae-seok,
the outcast at Daehan High.
It's a beautiful night.
Applause!
What is it? Do you need something?
No, sir.
How do you handle kids who misbehave?
The idea of discipline or guidance
gives you a headache.
Just give them penalty points.
Going by the book is easy.
Ever since corporal punishment was banned,
schools have been a mess.
If we discipline them even a bit,
they make such a fuss,
accusing us of human rights violations
and child abuse.
A teacher's passion?
We'd be lucky not to get stabbed
by a student with scissors.
-Two years ago…
-It happened to a teacher.
Exactly. That's what would happen.
It was horrific.
This isn't right. Come down!
-It's really dangerous!
-Get down!
-It's dangerous!
-Get down, for God's sake!
Hey, it's the police.
-Where?
-No way. Really?
-Are they here because of Park Dae-seok?
-So they're fucked?
No way are we fucked, fuckers!
Who did you say is fucked?
Fucking bastards!
Sit down! Sit the fuck down!
Welcome back to being the fucking outcast!
It looks best
on our dear Gyeong-min for sure.
Hey, you fucking bitch!
What's with that look?
Did you get your hopes up?
Like the fucking cops would question us
and throw us in jail?
You thought
you could finally relax at school?
Is that fucking it?
Huh?
Fucking hell! Losers never fucking learn.
You think this is a big fucking deal?
But fuck!
Nothing will change here.
Don't get angry. Okay?
He's got a lot to do,
being the outcast again.
We should congratulate him.
Gyeong-min, have you ever had a drink?
Hey, I'll buy you some.
Oh fuck!
We brought this with us.
Drink this, and you'll be an adult, okay?
-Don't.
-Let's drink up.
-It'll be fine. Drink up.
-Sit still.
Down it goes.
Man, what a waste!
I think he smells like alcohol.
Snap out of it, dude.
Go and wash your face.
Quiet.
Get a grip!
Sexy Gyeong-min!
MMA has made
my strength uncontrollable. Sorry.
It's…
-It's…
-Your stammering makes me feel worse.
-I said I'm sorry.
-It's fine.
Nah, you should just hit me too. Okay?
No, it's okay.
No, I'm not okay with it.
Bet you'll post about this later.
-No, I won't.
-Just hit me, dumbass.
Hit me. It's okay.
Hurry up and hit me.
-Hey, hit me.
-What's his deal?
Come on.
Man, sorry. How many times did I tell you?
Hit me. Slap me like this. Come on.
Hey, lift your head. Let me see.
Let me see, you fucking bastard.
Damn it.
You're fine. It's all good.
Hey, come here. Up you get.
Let me show you.
When you hit someone,
you look them in the eye.
Hit me.
Yeah!
Damn it.
Hey, let's try that again. Once more.
Fucking hell. Come on, don't cry.
Fine. I'll close my eyes.
Here.
Come on, hit me.
Just hit me, you fucking bastard!
Just hit me, you bastard. Come on.
Fuck, what the hell!
Hey, Gwang-su got hit.
Who is that?
-Who is it?
Did you just hit me?
Who the hell are you?
You a teacher?
Do not speak rudely to your elders!
Fuck.
Fucking hell!
Don't film this. Stop fucking filming!
You…
You must not run in the hallways.
Fuck you!
You must not cause
a disturbance at school.
-Jun-hyeong's here.
-It's Jun-hyeong.
What now?
Who the hell are you?
I was assigned to this school today.
So you're… a teacher.
Teachers shouldn't hit students.
Hey, record this.
-Okay.
-Guys, start filming.
Hey, get it on camera.
Can't you hit since you're on camera?
Hit me again, you crazy bastard.
All right. Fine, then.
Here. Gosh.
There you go.
Then I won't say no.
You know those things called Shorts?
TEACHING A LESSON
STUDENT ASSAULT
THE GRIM REAPER
WHACK! YET TO START
THRILLING! SPICY!
Now the other side!
SLAP
WHO'S THE ABUSIVE TEACHER?
SLAPPING ARTIST
SMILE OR GET F***ED
I'll get ahold of myself and behave.
-Heart pose.
-Teacher's coming.
-What is this?
-Heart pose.
-Move it!
-He's nuts.
What's going on? Who are you?
-What happened?
-What happened to your face?
-Who gave you the right to do this?
-Just a moment, please.
He says he's a newly appointed teacher.
Newly appointed? That's news to me.
Who the hell are you?
Hang on, it's here somewhere…
That's right.
It's around my neck.
I'm an inspector from the Korean
Educational Rights Protection Bureau.
My name is Na Hwa-jin.
The ERPB?
Have you heard of it?
No, I haven't.
Of course you haven't.
It was just established.
So what on earth is this bureau?
I should explain properly.
But it's my first time, you see.
We provide specialized guidance
to trashy schools
that pay off the police
to sweep incidents under the rug,
even when a student dies.
Not only did that never happen,
but is a teacher even allowed
to beat a kid like this?
It's allowed.
The ERPB inspector
holds one special authority.
"There is no limit whatsoever
to teaching methods."
Simply put,
if they listen to words,
you teach with words.
If they listen only after a beating,
then you teach by beating.
All right. Starting today,
the ERPB will teach this school…
a proper lesson.
TEACH YOU A LESSON
Gosh.
So this organization actually exists.
There seems to be
some kind of misunderstanding.
Bullies? School violence?
It's impossible for such things
to happen at this school.
Our students are of a very high standard.
Many parents are prominent
political or business figures,
including a National Assembly member.
Park Dae-seok was in second grade,
class 5, right?
As of today,
I'll be the teacher of that class.
The parents of our students
absolutely hate trouble and drama.
There will be uproar
if the students' grades drop.
Is that what you're afraid of?
Their grades?
The National Assembly member's son
is in that class.
You must know Assemblyman Ryu Gwang-pil.
The next presidential candidate.
A political titan.
You and I are both just salary earners.
That is a little scary, isn't it?
We should be scared.
He's a strong presidential candidate.
Mr. Kim.
If adults become afraid of children…
the world is doomed.
Fucking hell.
The ringing in my ears won't fucking stop.
Hey, the ERPB doesn't seem to exist.
If it does exist,
what the fuck are they going to do?
Fuck yeah.
They're all beneath your dad, aren't they?
You'll remember me from earlier.
I'm your homeroom teacher now.
We're fucked. Damn it.
Thanks for the warm welcome.
All right, let's take attendance.
-Ko Gyeong-chan.
-Here.
-Kim Gyeong-min.
-Kim Gwang-su.
-Here.
Oh, Gwang-su?
-Kim Na-rae.
-Here.
Ryu Jun-hyeong.
Park Dae-seok.
That's right.
Dae-seok's dead, isn't he?
Do you guys know
why Dae-seok ended up like that?
I heard he killed himself
because of stress from grades.
Is that right?
Or maybe Dae-seok killed himself
because one of you guys
bullied and ostracized him
until he couldn't take it anymore?
No, that's not it at all.
He was a stupid dumbass
and didn't want to take the mock exams.
So whoosh and splat,
he fell off the school roof and died.
Jesus, that trap of yours.
-It's so unkind.
-Wait a minute. Wait.
Don't you think?
You guys are really amazing.
All the talent ERPB is looking for
is right here.
You see teachers as morons.
You proudly uphold
the tradition of bullying.
You fucking bastard.
And you remain completely unfazed
even when a classmate dies.
You guys really are amazing. That's right.
You look remorseful.
Remorse is something you do
with your body, not your mind.
Shall we all get into a plank position?
On three.
Three!
Sit down.
Sit down!
The mock exams are around the corner.
Can you just start the lesson?
It's not like the ERPB
will own our grades.
I'm sure I said, "Three."
Oh no.
These jerks seem more afraid
of me than you.
Actually, this is great.
That means if one kid feels intimidated,
everyone else feels that way too.
But would that work? It's just that…
I don't fear a damn thing.
Fear comes from experience.
Let go of me.
Do you know who you're messing with?
Who else but a student?
Aren't you a student?
Every single day from now on…
will be like hell.
All right. Three!
This is the last time.
Three.
100 GLORIOUS YEARS OF DAEHAN
MAY IT THRIVE FOREVER
Thank you.
-Care for more?
-Thank you.
Enjoy your meal.
-Sure, no problem. Eat up.
-Thank you.
Thanks. Fuck off.
Sure. Eat up.
-Enjoy your meal.
-I will.
Thank you.
Man, how come everything you do
is just nasty?
What, still an a-hole at 18?
-Fucker.
-Do you want to be forced to the back?
No one is complaining.
Power is really scary, isn't it?
But power isn't for students.
If you want lunch,
go all the way to the back and line up.
Or you'll get none.
Oh my goodness.
Oh, sorry. I can't stand people
who play with their food.
Look at you.
Your clothes got all dirty.
You don't have ten school uniforms
for being a politician's son, right?
Come here. Let me get that.
Seriously, man.
This is why
you shouldn't play with your food.
There's some scallion on your face.
Put this on your head.
How pretty.
Jun-hyeong looks so cute like this.
Guys, it's photo time.
How about making some Shorts?
Just like our lovely Jun-hyeong here,
let's mind our manners
and eat with grateful hearts. Okay?
You made this mess. You clean it up.
Let's eat!
Line up!
You must be fucking excited.
No.
No what?
I asked what you mean by "no."
Huh?
Fuck off, you dumbass.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Fucking outcast.
Honey!
Who is it?
Is this the home
of Assemblyman Ryu Gwang-pil,
the strong presidential candidate?
Wow, these are actually real,
not just for decoration.
I mean, you always see these
in soap operas.
You know, I've always been curious.
It tastes great.
Jun-hyeong.
Now that Jun-hyeong is here,
please tell us what brings you here.
All right.
Our dear Jun-hyeong here
left without doing his cleaning duties.
"All students are equal.
Students shouldn't have power."
I've told him so many times. You brat.
Giving up power
seems like a hard thing to do.
"People as People, Politics as Politics."
This was your campaign slogan
in the last election, wasn't it?
I share a similar philosophy.
"Teachers as Teachers." You see?
"Students as Students," you punk!
So I'm just here to get the student
who didn't clean up, as a teacher should.
He's deliberately after me, picking on me,
trying to tie me
to the Park Dae-seok case!
That was delicious.
I'll take him with me,
as a teacher should.
Let's go. Come on.
You're making a mistake.
I'll guide Jun-hyeong well from now on
without any mistakes.
-Doors closing.
-They're closing.
You should hold it, punk!
I'll see you again. Come on, let's go.
-Let go!
-Which floor?
Doors closing.
The doors are so slow.
These should remain a mess
so that we can keep the story moving.
But they're too clean for that.
You do well when you try. Okay, then.
Finish up here
and put those cleaning supplies away.
STUDENT RECORD
STUDENT NAME: PARK DAE-SEOK
Choi Gang-seok.
It seems Minister Choi Gang-seok
took the lead in setting up the ERPB.
And it seems
you're not a qualified teacher.
I'm treated as a teacher
during the investigation period.
I'm sure you already know that.
You'll have to explain what happened
to my son's head.
Well, I'm not sure.
I told him to clean the toilet,
not to slam his head against it.
Are you saying my son hurt himself
on purpose to frame you?
He might find it easy to hit others,
but he must've been scared to hit himself.
How should I put this?
His injury looks forced.
You act like nothing scares you.
If a doctor is afraid of their patients,
they can't treat them properly.
If a lawyer is afraid of their clients,
they can't defend them properly.
So if a teacher
is afraid of their students,
can they teach them properly?
I'm sure you fully understand
what it means for me to get involved.
The ERPB is a national organization.
You'll have to take on the nation.
It's something I'm well-versed in.
That's great.
So you're the one
who snitched to the ERPB, you bitch.
It wasn't me.
Yeah, right.
Jun-hyeong's father came to school,
all fucking because of you.
You want to join Dae-seok?
-It really wasn't me. Really…
-Here.
Hey.
-Are you sure?
-Hey, come here.
Whether you fucking snitched or not
doesn't matter.
Fucking hell. I treated you…
Fuck, I was so good to you.
-Hey, just go.
-Fucking bitch!
-Get lost!
-You fucking bitch.
You fucker!
Hey, look here.
-Lift your head.
-Fucking bastard.
-Hey, come on.
-You fucker.
Oh man, kiddo. You're a real handful.
What next? Let go or pull?
Pull!
Where are your manners?
Please pull!
Follow me.
It looks like you always get beaten up
by Jun-hyeong's gang. Right?
How long do you plan
on getting beaten up for?
Don't talk like that
when you've got no idea.
What if I do fight back?
Do you think that changes anything?
Who said anything about fighting back?
Make a break for it.
Those who tell you to fight back
clearly have never been
beaten up themselves.
But it'll only get worse.
You can run away then too.
So just keep running away forever?
You're right. You can't keep running away.
So you need to
tell an adult.
It's no use.
Keep telling them until it's of use.
There are good adults out there too.
Now, for this reason,
you'll start intense running training
starting today.
Do you see that soccer goal?
Run there and back. You have ten seconds.
Sorry?
Run. Why aren't you running?
Run!
Run. Come on, faster.
I said faster!
I'll set the dog on you.
-Where's the dog?
-Me. I'm a mad dog.
Hurry up, man!
Are you sure you can manage on your own?
Yes, sir.
That's right. You can do it.
You did it earlier too. That's it. Good.
Nicely set out.
Maybe it's your experience as a gofer.
Your service is perfect.
You're just like them, you know.
No, I'm not, kiddo.
I'm a teacher,
and they're just pathetic bullies.
They're not all that pathetic.
They're extremely powerful.
Jun-hyeong's father
can ruin a whole family without trying.
Don't worry about
that kind of thing, all right?
I've got big guns backing me too.
Lucky you, having such a thing.
Gyeong-min.
You've got big guns backing you too.
Who?
Don't you know?
Look around you.
They're not that far. Look closer.
Who would be a student's big gun?
Their teacher.
Seriously, man.
Here, your supportive big gun
has peeled it just for you.
Right, thank you.
Gyeong-min, how is it
that you don't have a single friend
you can confide in? Huh?
I wasn't always ostracized.
Why haven't you told your parents?
Because they'd be worried?
DARLING SON
ENJOY YOUR DAY!
Oh, I don't know.
Just eat your ramyeon. It'll get soggy.
All right.
MINISTRY OF EDUCATION
Wait! Just a moment, Mr. Ryu!
Hello.
What brings you here, Assemblyman Ryu?
The Educational Rights Protection Bureau.
Is it true you created it?
Well, I suppose I did.
Would you like a cup of tea?
I didn't come here to drink tea.
Don't stand there. Take a seat.
Why on earth did you create such a thing?
Because I felt bad.
I'm sure you remember too.
There was a case two years ago
where a teacher was murdered at school
by their own student.
I thought teachers' rights
needed to be clearly established
so nothing like that happens again.
But why Daehan High of all places?
My son is suffering
because of it right now.
Does your son go to Daehan High?
Oh dear.
The inspector has been going too far.
If this is publicized,
public criticism will grow fierce.
Nothing good can come from this.
So why don't you just end it here?
Well, there are a lot of eyes on us,
and the organization
has just been established.
How about we just wait a little longer?
You know I have respect for you, Minister.
I'm telling you all this for your sake.
You wouldn't want to retire from politics
over something like this.
A father would do anything
for his child.
This is Ryu Gwang-pil
of the Happiness Hope Party.
Please support him.
-Thank you.
-What's the time?
Shouldn't he be here by now?
-Come on, set your phones to vibrate.
-Sorry.
People as People, Politics as Politics.
What's this?
"Using aides for personal matters"?
"Bribery in exchange
for local election nomination"?
-Sexual harassment?
-What's this about?
Ryu Gwang-pil!
Thank you for taking the time to come.
Do you admit to the bribery allegations?
-What do you mean?
-There has been a tip-off.
It's about your sexual misconduct.
Is it true that you engaged
in illegal property speculation?
What the hell is going on?
I'll look into it. You should go.
-Hurry and block them off here!
-Don't push!
Do you admit it? Please say something!
Assemblyman Ryu!
Damn it.
What's going on?
It's noisy out there.
There's no need for you to know.
It'd be best if you left now.
You must be a little slow on the uptake.
Don't tell me
you're behind this?
Who put you up to this?
It took me two years…
to create the ERPB.
It turns out
two years is quite a long time.
RYU GWANG-PIL
UNOFFICIAL REPORT
RECORDING OF VICTIM INTERVIEW
RYU GWANG-PIL
NOMINATION CORRUPTION REPORT
Are you crazy?
You and I are on the same side!
We're in the same party, for fuck's sake!
Assemblyman Ryu.
There is no such thing as sides
when it comes to education.
Was I your target from the very beginning?
Just why?
What the hell have I done so wrong?
Are you serious or full of baloney?
Your wrongdoings
should be all over the news by now.
Shit, this is fucked up!
There are so many people
worse than me out there!
So why the hell are you doing this to me?
That's because
when you fall,
your son falls too.
You really should've educated
that brat of yours better.
-Minister.
-Please step aside.
Damn it!
-Are you there?
-Sir!
Just a moment!
The National Assembly approved
an arrest motion of Ryu Gwang-pil,
who faces corruption allegations.
Furthermore, there have been allegations
that Ryu's son was responsible
for the school bullying
that resulted
in the death of his classmate,
shocking the public even more.
This case, which almost got buried,
surfaced through an investigation
by the ERPB.
The ERPB, a new agency
led by the Minister of Education,
will handle the independent
and prompt protection of teachers' rights.
It is responsible for receiving reports,
investigating, and responding--
This might also turn
into a political issue.
Would you be okay?
I'll take all the bullets and missiles.
You just get the job done.
Like you've ever been shot.
If you get shot,
you'll actually die of pain.
It's just a metaphor.
I won't really take it.
I was using a metaphor too.
Thank you for your effort.
Hey, did you guys see this?
As of today, the Daehan High outcast is…
Cutie Pie! Applause!
Hey, it looks best on you so far.
Our dear Jun-hyeong, where are you going?
He's fucking nothing without his dad!
It stinks like trash.
OUTCAST STICK
It's not your fault.
Gyeong-min.
When Dae-seok became the outcast,
I was relieved.
When he died,
I couldn't help but smile.
I thought I'd be able to break free
from this hell.
I'm no different from them.
Yes, you are, kiddo.
You were picked on for no reason.
Those who bullied you
and the adults who knew but silenced you
are the ones at fault.
So don't be regretful
or feel remorseful.
-He's crazy!
-Fuck this!
I recorded everything, you motherfucker.
Die, you fucking bastards.
Jun-hyeong!
Jun-hyeong, I'm sorry!
Fuck this!
-The ERPB is here.
-It's him.
We're safe now.
You just can't own up, can you?
I told you, didn't I?
Remorse is something you do
with your body, not your mind.
Are you crazy?
The gasoline.
What about it?
Isn't this why you poured it?
Please help me! I'm sorry!
I was wrong!
Please help me!
It's all my fault.
I'm sorry!
Why the hell are you taking it
this far with me? Why?
And what about you?
Why did you take it so far with Dae-seok?
Dae-seok was afraid of dying too.
Just like you.
But he still made that choice
because of a scumbag like you.
WITH VIGOR, HOLDING HOPEFUL DREAMS CLOSE
If you're finding the bullying
so difficult to deal with,
how about moving to a different school?
Excuse me?
Why should my child move to a new school?
The bully should switch schools.
Why should the victim go?
You can't just cancel your order
all of a sudden like this.
I just don't understand what's going on
with our vendors.
I'm sorry.
-Please go easy on my dad.
-Get lost.
-Shut up.
-Ask your dad.
Ask him to go easy on my dad
this one time.
Why are you asking me?
I'm just a helpless jerk without my dad.
I'm really sorry.
What can I do to make it up to you?
I'll do whatever you say.
Go fucking die, then.
Making the students
realize the full extent of their actions
by giving them
a taste of their own medicine
and making them take responsibility
for those actions.
This is the true education…
that the ERPB seeks.
But no matter what you do to make amends…
Dae-seok
can never be brought back to life.
The least you can do is carry that burden
for the rest of your life.
That's the only way to make it fair.
This is the hell you created.
See how you like living there.
The police reopened Dae-seok's case
and arrested those who bullied Dae-seok,
including Ryu Jun-hyeong.
You told me to trust you,
you fucking bitch!
And for the first time…
He's not here.
…the principal took accountability
like a grown-up.
-I said he's not here.
-Mr. Kim!
What are you doing down there?
On the ERPB website,
Ryu Jun-hyeong's bullying
was made public for everyone to see.
And they say those records
will never be erased
unless the victims forgive them.
That was how the ERPB
ended their guidance at Daehan High.
After that day, we never saw
the inspector at school again.
THE LATE CHOI GA-YUN
1995.07.25 - 2024.11.27
WE WILL NOT FORGET
Subtitle translation by: Lisa Kim